PROFILE

Highly motivated software engineer with significant experience in research and development of secure cloud applications. Strong in design and integration problem-solving skills. Skilled in developing business plans, requirements specifications and architectural systems research. More than 10 years experience with Google Cloud Technologies. An excellent team player with attitude, strong written and verbal communications.

EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead TARYA FINTECH

March 2020 - Present

As a Senior Software Engineer Team Lead I was responsible for :

- Led a dynamic team of 5-8 software engineers, fostering a culture of innovation and technical excellence. Provided mentorship, guidance, and technical expertise to team members, enabling them to excel in their roles. Responsible for Investor management part of the application
- Investor management includes Investment settings,
 Financing/Trading/Liquification of the loans investments, Investments status,
 Depositis and Withdraws transactions, Investor and Investor Agent Fronted dashboard(AngularJS), Investor Reporting, Notifications
- Resolved complex technical challenges and critical issues that arose during project development. Leveraged analytical skills and deep technical knowledge to identify and implement solutions.
- Continuously sought opportunities to optimize processes, reduce technical debt, and enhance system performance.
- Organizing the teams' task schedule according to the priority
- Supporting the production and teams dev/QA environments
- Responsible for managing and supporting release flow (making production release and hot fixes)
- Investigating and fixing bugs
- Onboarding new team members

Some of the main tools and technologies that were used:

- Microservices architecture, REST API, Open API, Async communication, Event driven communication
- Java 8
- Spring boot, Spring cloud, Hibernate, JOOQ
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Docker Container, container management : Docker Swarm, Docker Compose
- AWS, Oauth2

Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead CLOUWAY LTD

Feb 2011 - Feb 2020

As a Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead at Clouway Ltd, I assumed a multifaceted role with a focus on driving innovation, ensuring software excellence, and leading cross-functional teams to deliver impactful solutions. My responsibilities included:

- Led a dynamic team of 5-9 software engineers, fostering a culture of innovation and technical excellence. Provided mentorship, guidance, and technical expertise to team members, enabling them to excel in their roles.
- Collaborated closely with Product Managers to comprehend use cases and user stories, playing a pivotal role in shaping the architectural design of products eco system to be developed.
- Worked closely with senior leadership to align technical strategies with the company's long-term goals. Contributed to the development of the technology roadmap and ensured that technical decisions supported the organization's



Senior Software Engineer / R&D Team Lead

- mlesikov@gmail.com
- **J** +359 899 368 003
- mlesikov.github.io/cv/
- in mihail-lesikov-49147243
- mlesikov
- Veliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria
- Resume PDF

EDUCATION

MSc in Informatics, Information Technology Systems

St. Cyril and St. Methodius University of Veliko Tarnovo 2009 - 2012

BSc in Informatics / Socrates Erasmus Program

Leeds Metropolitan university UK 2007

BSc in Informatics

University of Veliko Tarnovo 2004 - 2009

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Bulgarian (Native)

vision.

- Create, implement and maintain a continuous improvement plan
- Understanding the use cases (and/or user stories) in order to oversee the design of the architecture for the products to be built
- Ensure that the skills and experience of Software Development and IT teams are consistent with its scientific, technological and business needs for providing quality in present and future services
- Continuously sought opportunities to optimize processes, reduce technical debt, and enhance system performance.
- Resolved complex technical challenges and critical issues that arose during product/eco system development. Leveraged analytical skills and deep technical knowledge to identify and implement solutions.
- Spearheaded research initiatives, staying at the forefront of emerging technologies and industry trends. Implemented cutting-edge solutions to solve complex technical challenges, driving innovation within the organization.

Some of the main tools and technologies that were used:

- Java, Kotlin
- Microservice, Oauth2, CQRS, Agile
- Gradle, Google Cloud Platform(Google BigQuery, Cloud Pub/Subs, etc.)
- ReactJS, Angular 1.5
- Spark Java

Software Engineer (Full Stack)

Feb 2009 - Feb 2011

CLOUWAY LTD

As a software engineer, my main responsibility was to develop and maintain high scalable servers of the company projects. One of them was TelcoNg BSS project, which provides quality service for thousands of subscribers. The project was one of the first enterprise project that uses the Google App Engine and the earliest version of the Google Cloud Services. The frontend of the project was built with GWT.

Some of the main tools that were used:

- Java, Maven, Google app engine, GWT, Sitebricks,
- Scrum, TDD, Design Patterns
- · Rest Api, Google Cloud Datastore
- Postgree SQL, Apache Tomcat, Jetty, HTML & CSS, Javascript

PROJECTS

TARYA Fintech Loan Management Solution - Software solution(end-to-end lending platform), designed to automate and improve the entire loan lifecycle.

TARYA P2P - Tarya is a solid investment platform that yields over time consistent positive returns to its investors.

Politis - Cloud based, mobile and web sales platform.

TelcoNG BSS - Cloud based, end-to-end Bussiness support software solution. CRM, billing and self-service domains

TelcoNG WSS - Cloud based, workforce management software solution.

TelcoNG Accounts - Authentication & authorization, Oauth2 based platform part of TelcoNG Framework